### RESUME

# Yogender Kumar

Email: yogender3107@gmail.com

Mob: +91 7790915264



## **Career Objective**

I am proficient in collaborating with team members and remote clients to effectively conduct requirements gathering and optimize solutions as per the requirements. With 5+ years of experience, I would like to work in an organization where I can use all my skills for the holistic development of the organization and self.

## **Technical Skills**

- Programming Languages: Javascript, NodeJs, React, Redux, React-Native, Java
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, MacOS
- Database: MongoDB, MySQL, Elastic
- Tools: IntelliJ Idea, Visual Studio Code etc

## **Work Experience**

- Software Developer, Skuad Lab India Pvt. Ltd, Gurugram
- Software Developer, Appstreet Software Pvt. Ltd, Gurugram
- Associate IT, Daffodil Software Pvt. Ltd, Hisar

April 2020 to Present Jan 2019 to April 2020 July 2016 - Dec 2018

# <u>Achievements</u>

- Me and my team received Alchemist Award for our hard work and solutions
- Performer of the year 2021 by Cardekho.

# **Projects Summary**

**Connex:** This system is used to design for selling and purchasing new cars from gaadi stores at a reasonable price.

#### Responsibilities

- · Responsible for API integration with UI.
- · Responsible for managing backend schema for different entity used
- Responsible for business understanding and then implementing accordingly.
- · Defined and developed core logic before starting any module

Technologies: NodeJS, MySQL

**Hire SKUAD:** This system was developed to design the hiring process for both Skuad and the companies that are looking for resources for their project. It maintains all the candidate's records including their resume details and the interview track

#### Responsibilities

- · Responsible for UI development
- · Responsible for managing backend schema for different entity used
- · Responsible for the integration of identity service with Hire
- · Defined and developed core logic before starting any module
- · Worked on google integration
- Enabled cookie based authentication

Technologies: NodeJS, ReactJS, Elastic, Mongo

**Pay SKUAD:** This system was developed to design the contracts between two parties and signing up the agreement on same

#### Responsibilities

- · Responsible for UI development
- Responsible for managing backend schema for different entity used
- · Responsible for integration of identity service with Pay
- · Defined and developed core logic before starting any module
- Worked upon google integration
- · Enabled cookie based authentication

Technologies: NodeJS, ReactJS, Mongo

**Identity Service:** This system was developed to provide the login service to all the other micro services that our team is working upon. Common login for Pay, Hire and any other services build for Skuad provide us that service for login

### Responsibilities

- · Responsible for UI development
- · Managed different service login with identity service
- · Responsible for managing backend schema for different entity used
- · Defined and developed core logic before starting any module
- · Enabled cookie based authentication

Technologies: NodeJS, ReactJS, Mongo, Firebase

Linex System: This system is designed to provide loan to dealers via the auction systems(Connx)

as well as procured from open market(GCloud). I worked as a backend developer in NodeJS for

building new features

Responsibilities

Responsible for managing backend Schema for different entity used

Managed transaction for the systema and maintaining ledger items

Defined and developed core logic before starting any module

Google based authentication

Technologies: NodeJS, PSQL

Applane Framework: This framework uses react, react-redux, node, mongodb, express for

designing and implementing web and native applications quickly. It consists of different reusable

components like router, list, table, form etc. By using this framework, user can start working on

his project at a faster pace

Responsibilities

· Responsible for managing backend Schema for different entities used

Responsible for managing report cards and attendance of the students

Defined and developed core logic before starting any module

Google app engine for application monitoring

Technologies: Java, SQL

Applane for Education: This is the platform for the schools where user can manage their

employees as well as their students moving them from pen and paper to digital world.

Responsibilities

Responsible for managing backend Schema for different entity used

Responsible for managing reportcards and attendance of the students

Defined and developed core logic before starting any module

Google app engine for application monitoring

Technologies: Nodejs, SQL

Applane for Education React: This platform is used for schools where user can manage their

employees as well as their students moving them from pen paper to digital world. We have used

React, react-native, redux and mobx, Node.js. Below are the applications:

Manaze uses applane framework, node, mongodb, react, react-native and redux.js. It is an online

portal for managing daily tasks, projects, employees, salaries and attendances of employees etc.

Manaze V2 uses applane framework new design, node, mongodb, react, react-native, react-

router.js. It is an enhancement on previous version and new features(http://web3.manaze.io)

#### Responsibilities

- · Responsible for managing backend schema for different entities used
- · Responsible for managing report cards and attendance of the students
- Defined and developed core logic before starting any module
- · Google app engine for application monitoring

Technologies: React, NodeJS, Mongo

**Yellow.live Website:** Yellow.live mobile application is used for tracking school buses. It is a fully responsive website that uses tech like react, next and node.js

#### Responsibilities:

- · Responsible for managing backend schema for different entities used
- · Responsible for tracking the student till they reach school
- · Defined and developed core logic before starting any module
- · Responsible for google map integration api

Technologies: Reactjs, Nodejs, Mongo

**Autoload Website:** This website is used for tracking of manufacturer transport. It is a fully responsive website using tech like react, next and node.js

#### Responsibilities:

- · Responsible for managing backend schema for different entity used
- · Responsible for tracking the trucks till they reach the destination
- · Defined and developed core logic before starting any module
- · Responsible for google map integration api

Technologies: Reactjs, Nodejs, Mongo

# **Educational Qualification**

Qualification	School / College	Percentage	Year
B.Tech	Poornima Institute of Engineering and Technology, Jaipur.	70%	2016
th 12	Army Public School, Jodhpur.	77.4%	2012
th 10	Army Public School, Jodhpur.	82.4%	2009

### **Personal Details**

Date of Birth : 31-07-1994

Father's Name : Late Mr.

Shiv Kumar

Sex : Male

Marital Status : Married

Nationality : Indian

Language Known : Hindi (native),

English

## **Declaration**

I hereby declare that information given above is true in all respect. I will be solely responsible for any discrepancy or false information if found.

Date:

Place: Chirawa, Rajasthan Yogender Kumar

Yogender